Walt Kuhn Family Papers and Armory Show
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Walt Kuhn Family Papers, 1859-1978, Series 4:; (Box 3-26, 32-35, OV 39-55; 25.8 linear feet)
  - Audio Recordings, 1965, 1969, 4.12:; (Box 26; 0.2 linear feet; 8 audio reels [circa 24 hours], 1 audio cassette)
    - Brenda Kuhn's Recordings, 1965, (2 of 4) (Box 26, Folder 8)
      Reel 3, Side 1: Brenda Kuhn discusses Armory Show records and Walt Kuhn letters from 1936 to 1941. Selected subjects include Brenda's decision to donate papers to AAA; recollections of Fort Lee, NJ, 1909-1919; Ogunquit, ME house; 18th St. studio; Kuhn's animal art; circumstances of Philip Guston taking over WK studio in 1957; La Salle Spier; Spier home in Chevy Chase, MD; Kuhn's searches for landscape subjects; Arthur B. Davies second family as David A. Owen, and his daughter, Ronven Owen; Kuhn's cooking talents and his parents' Brooklyn restaurant, the International House; stage celebrities.
      Reel 3, Side 2: Brenda Kuhn discusses Walt Kuhn letters from 1941 and 1944. Selected subjects include Kuhn's automobiles; painting methods; Frank di Gioia; Brenda's epilepsy; Vera Kuhn.
      Reel 4, Side 1: Brenda discusses photographs and Walt Kuhn letters from 1936 to 1944. Selected subjects include Walt Kuhn's transition from cartoonist to fine artist; Kuhn family photographs; community of artists in Fort Lee, NJ, including Jules Pascin, Pop Hart, Paul Bransom, Rudy Dirks; meeting of Walt and Vera Kuhn; Penguin Club Kuhn's Maine landscape paintings; reading habits; Cape Neddick, ME; Perkins Cove, ME and the Laurent family; Alfred Frankfurter; onset of Kuhn's mental illness.
      Reel 4, Side 2: Brenda Kuhn discusses Walt Kuhn publication Fifty Paintings, and letters from 1920 and 1938 to 1947. Selected subjects include watching her father paint; Kuhn's hobby of carving toys for children; Kuhn's experiences at Lake Buel, MA; Kuhn's guitar-playing; Brenda's plans for a museum in Cape Neddick; Kuhn's smoking habits; Edna St. Vincent de Millay purchase of "Mario"; Kuhn's illness and idea for "State of Maine Follies"; Vera's record-keeping habits; Kuhn's teaching, especially John Laurent; Frank di Gioia.
    - Brenda Kuhn's Recordings, 1965, (3 of 4) (Box 26, Folder 9)
      Reel 5, Side 1: Selected subjects include Durand-Ruel Galleries; Margery Petit Caron; Kuhn's clown drawings and use of pass to circus; Kuhn's costume collection.
      Reel 5, Side 2: Brenda Kuhn discusses Walt Kuhn letters from 1938-1948. Selected subjects include Walt Kuhn's painting techniques; Paul Bransom, social life at Clark's restaurant in Maine; Ogunquit, ME Playhouse; Kuhn's social life, family life, and involvement with show people; Kuhn's automobiles; Kuhn's rivalry with Picasso; relationship with Gary Cooper; Kuhn's time on Florida's Gold Coast; relationship with Paul and Minna Mellon.
      Reel 6, Side 1: Selected subjects include Walt Kuhn's reading habits; Cape Neddick, ME; Kuhn family's relationships with the Glackens family; Edith Halpert; confusion over Kuhn's birth date.
      Reel 6, Side 2: Brenda Kuhn muses on prospects for Walt Kuhn centenary and publications; Brenda Kuhn interviews Grace Jones Sarka, who describes her relationship to Walt Kuhn beginning in 1903, and their artists' community centered around the 23rd St. studio in New York.
    - Brenda Kuhn's Recordings, 1965, (4 of 4) (Box 26, Folder 10)
      Reel 7 (labeled 6B): Brenda Kuhn attends Elizabeth Navis day at Wichita Museum; discusses the Murdoch collection; Kuhn's relationship with Maurice Prendergast and William Glackens; importance to Kuhn of Eakins' painting The Gross Clinic. (Note: Side 2 of this reel is not recorded)
      Reel 8 (labeled #7), Side 1: Garnett McCoy interviews Brenda Kuhn, November 19, 1965. Selected subjects include Kuhn's feelings about his contemporaries and artist circles; Kuhn's personality and aesthetic, and his attitudes towards art, politics, family, religion, Jews, etc.; Kuhn's work with collectors, especially John Quinn; Penguin Club; vaudeville; Kuhn's 14th St. studio; Clara Davidge; Frederick James Gregg; writing and distribution of "The Story of the Armory Show;" discovery of Armory Show records and Milton Brown; Arthur B. Davies; brief recollections of Edward and Jo Hopper, Edith and William Glackens, Charles Sheeler, John Sloan, personality and death of George Luks, Walter Pach, Abraham Walkowitz, Georgia O'Keeffe, Louis Bouché, George Bellows, Robert Henri; Kuhn in Florida.
      Reel 8 (labeled #7), Side 2: Garnett McCoy interview with Brenda Kuhn, cont. Selected subjects include relationships with dealers Annie Montross, Edith Halpert, the Harrimans, Durand-Ruel, and Maynard Walker; Albert Freueh, Marius de Zayas; Kuhn's attitude towards critics; Kuhn's public relations philosophy; the dissolution of the Association of American Painters and Sculptors; Jules Pascin; Mary Roberts; Kuhn's mental illness; Vera Kuhn; disposition of the estate.
    - "Walt Kuhn Day," July 13, 1969, (1 audio cassette) (Box 26, Folder 11)